export const infoArrayData = [
    {
      item: 1,
      title: "Paper",
      content: [
        {
          question:"How to recycle paper?",
          answer: "When you are recycleing a paper is important to remove any food scraps and plastic packaging that may be inside the packaging. It is necessary to rinse the milk carton to avoid odor pollution and then fold all the packaging together and put it in one square so that it takes up less space. Plastic stoppers may be carried by milk carton.Every paper goes to the green barrel.",
        },
        {
          question: "Which types of paper can be recycled?",
          answer: [
            {
              item: "Corrugated cardboard: All corrugated cardboard, for example cardboard boxes, pizza boxes and detergent boxes!"
            },
            {
              item: "Corrugated cardboard is known by waves that are visible if its edges are examined. It is okay for the corrugated cardboard to be printed, plastic-coated and colorful."
            },
            {
              item: "Plain cardboard: There is packaging for the outside of breakfast cereals, egg trays, kitchen and toilet cubicles and biscuit packages.",
            },
            {
              item: "Newspapers: Newspapers, magazines, all kinds of advertising papers, envelopes, office paper and so on."
            },
            {
              item: "Paper staples do not need to be cleaned."
            },
            {
              item: " What else can i do? It’s always good to fold the paper so that they take up less space."
            },
          ],
        },
      ],
      
    },
    {
      item: 2,
      title: "Metal",
      content: [
        {
          question: "How to recycle metal? ",
          answer: [
            {
              item: "You do not need to remove postage stamps, plastic caps or handles. Metal still needs to be in the majority. You dont need back for metals and cans when it goes to the barrel."
            },
            {
              item: "Egg irons, e.g. knives and scissors, must be returned to the Category so that it does not harm anyone during recycleing. All larger metal parts e.g. pots, pans, garden tools, lawn mowers, etc. shall also be returned to recycle center."
            },
          ],
        },
        {
          question: " Which types of metal can be recycled?",
          answer: "Cans, lids, caps, aluminum foil, aluminum boxes of alcohol candles and many other small items made of metal fall into this category."
        },
      ], 
      
      

    },
    {
      item: 3,
      title: "Glass",
      content: [
        {
          question: "How to recycle glass?",
          answer: [
            {
              item: "Return all glass to special collection points and containers at nearby locations. The containers must be empty and clean."
            },
            {
              item: "Always be careful with glass - it can cause accidents. This material does not go in the recycling bin."
            },
            {
              item: "Unfortunately, glass is not recycled, but experiments have been made using crushed glass in asphalt. It can be ground down and used as a filler in various projects and can be used as sand or gravel."
            },
            {
              item: "Light bulbs are not classified as glass but as hazardous waste and therefore do not belong in this recycling category."
            },
          ],
        },
        {
          question: " Which types of glass can be recycled?",
          answer: " What is classified as glass is: window glass, glass packaging, jars (remove metal lids), flower pots, glass bottles, perfume glasses, mirrors, ceramics and dishes."
        },
      ],    
    },



    {
      item: 4,
      title: "Plastic",
      content: [
        {
          question: "How to recycle plastic?",
          answer: "All empty plastic containers, plastic material should be sorted from household waste. A Green bin for plastics can be ordered from the Reykjavik City. Drop off centres and SORPA waste collection area and Drop off centres collect plastics."
        },
        {
          question: "What else can i do?",
          answer: "It is important to remove any leftover food from the containers; 99% clean is sufficient.Any food left in the containers should be placed in the organic waste bin. Note that it is okay to put clean styrofoam food packaging into the green bag."
        },
      ],
      
      

    },
    {
      item: 5,
      title: "Batteries",
      content: [
        {
          question: "How to recycle batteries?",
          answer: "In most areas you will need to take batteries to a recycling centre or a collection point in a supermarket, a DIY centre or even your local shop.Batteries can be taken to Sorpa waste collection sites."
        },
        {
          question: "Which types of batteries can be recycled",
          answer: "All household batteries including 'button' batteries from watches. Battery packs from laptops, mobile phones, power tools and remote control units.Car batteries should be recycled at designated collection points."
        },
        {
          question: "What else can i do?",
          answer: " Use rechargeable batteries wherever possible or plug electrical equipment into the mains electricity. Try to buy appliances that use renewable energy - a wind-up radio or torch, dynamo bicycle lights or a solar powered calculator."
        },
      ],
       
      
    },
    {
      item: 6,
      title: "Organic",
      content: [
        {
          question: "What can i do with organic?",
          answer: [
            {
              item: "The brown barrel is intended for organic kitchen waste that goes to compost."
            },
            {
              item: "Organic garden waste can be returned to a container area in municipalities, but in the case of small quantities it can be placed in a maize bag in the brown barrel."
            },
            {
              item: "Sorting instructions for the brown barrel are available here."
            },
            {
              item: "Bones and meat offal that may contain brain or spinal cord tissue from sheep or cattle should be disposed of with general waste. The same applies to large bones, e.g. of lamb thighs."
            },
          ],
        },
        {
          question: "Which types of organic food can be recycled?",
          answer: "Fruit and fruit peel,Vegetables and vegetable peelings,Eggs and eggshell,Cooked meat and fish leftovers,Tea bag,Wooden toothpicks,Coffee basket."
        },
        {
          question: "What else can i do?",
          answer: " If you do not have a brown barrel, you can get a container for home composting from us. 30-35% of household waste is organic waste that can be recycled, for example 1 kilogram of organic waste about 0.6 kilograms of compost."
        }
      ],

  
      
    },
    {
      item: 7,
      title: "Medicine",
      content: [
        {
          question: "What can i do with medicine?",
          answer: "  Medicine should never mix with other household waste. Unopened, unused and out-of-date medicines should be returned to pharmacies for disposal.Inhalers should not be put in the waste bin as they contain gases which are harmful to the environment.They can be brought to Sorpa‘s waste collection sites."
        },
        {
          question: "How to dispose of unwanted medicines?",
          answer: "Return them to a pharmacy or chemist for safe disposal.Do not flush medicines down the toilet.The cardboard box that houses the blister packs can be recycled, as can any paper inserts."
        },
      ],
      

    },
    {
      item: 8,
      title: "Clothes",
      content: [
        {
          question: "How to recycle unwanted clothes and textiles?",
          answer: "  Waste drop off centres sites have containers from the Red Cross that collect used clothes and textiles. Take textile products there instead of putting it in your household waste. Here you can find your nearest."
        },
        {
          question: "What else can i do?",
          answer: [
            {
              item: "Drop off your unwanted items at recycling points and clothing and textile banks in supermarket. Many high street retailers such as Primark and M&S now offer clothing donation banks in-store. These are sometimes called 'bring back schemes'. This means that next time you pop out to the shops, you can drop off a bag of your old clothes."
            },
            {
               item: "Donate items to charities and re-use organisations. If your items are good quality, why not sell them? Sell your unwanted items at online places. Some shops will buy second hand clothes such as evening wear and vintage items."
            },
          ],
        },
      ],
    },


    {
      item: 9,
      title: "Bottles",
      content: [
        {
          question: "How to recycle plastic bottles and cans?",
          answer: "Bottles and cans from beverages which bear recycling fees should be returned to Endurvinnslan or toone of Sorpa´s waste collection areas."
        },
        {
          question: "What else can i do?",
          answer: "Squash bottles to save space.Empty and rinse bottles. Left over foods or liquids can contaminate other recyclables and if bottles contain liquid they may not be recycled as deemed too heavy by the automated sorting process. Liquid can also damage the machinery.Leave on labels - these will be removed in the process."
        },
      ],
    },  
  ];